<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Devops on Namc's blog</title><link>/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in Devops on Namc's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 06:25:12 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using the right tools for an Observable Kubernetes Cluster</title><link>/posts/cloud-observability-ii/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 06:25:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/cloud-observability-ii/</guid><description>In the last part, we saw commonly used terms and tools in CNCF landscape for making your Cloud Infrastructure observable. In this section we will read about how we can use those concepts and handful of tools to get started.
Creating a very basic and bare-minimum observable infrastructure Considering that the system engineer is somewhat well-versed with cloud-friendly observability tools, let’s look at some tools that can help lay-down a sound foundation for system observability</description></item><item><title>Understanding Observability (and the family) in Cloud Infrastructure</title><link>/posts/cloud-observability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 16:25:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/cloud-observability/</guid><description>This blog post is divided in two parts -
Understanding the terminlogies in Observability Ecosystem and corresponding tools How you can use some bare-minimum tooling to improve observability in your kubernetes cluster Terminologies in Observability Ecosystem With a huge shift towards Kubernetes and therefore, a distributed systems service architecture, we see a constant need to have solid observability practices. This ranges from application-level monitoring to OS &amp;amp; Network monitoring, as well as capturing telemetry and kubernetes events.</description></item></channel></rss>